Joubert Guimarães de Assis "RedRat"

Software Engineer, DevOps, Cosplayer, Speaker, Opensource community evangelist

About me

I am eternal trainee of life that works over 10 years ago in technology area, with focus in engineering and architecture of software and with specialization in financial systems and DevOps, moreover speaker around the world, always receiving and sharing the knowledge with wisdom.

Education

UNA University Center – Information Systems Bachelor, 2009 to 2013.

Federal University of Minas Gerais – Extension course in Modern Software Engineering, 2021.

- Certificate ID: 1005.0509.0704.0513.1624.0061, URL: https://sistemas.ufmg.br/cediex/home.seam **Federal University of Minas Gerais** Extension course in Software Testing, 2021.
- Certificate ID: 1508.0806.0407.0916.1832.6604, URL: https://sistemas.ufmg.br/cediex/home.seam

Professional experience

Consulting Software Engineer at Edvisor – April/2022 to present

Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada (Remote)

- Creation of crawling to automation of business flow inside lambda functions when provider doesn't have API's for integration.
- Creation of scripts to automation of database restore in other environments.
- Improvements in flows of infrastructure as a code "laaC" automation.
- Technical support for other development teams.

Technologies and tools used: Typescript, Javascript, Puppeteer, Crawling, SST, Serverless, NodeJS, Meteor, AWS, GCP, CircleCI, Datadog, Sentry, Github Actions, MongoDB, Docker, Docker Compose, Metabase.

Consulting Software Engineer at Medportal – March/2022 to present

Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Remote)

- Integration with AWS Cognito to provide authentication and authorization flow in API routes.
- Implementation of new accounts register flow using SAGA pattern.
- Implementation of forgot password flow, with configurable sending e-mail and expiration flow.
- Improvements in validations in routes related to user management.

Technologies and tools used: Golang, AWS Cognito, PostgreSQL, Memcached, Sendgrid, Docker, Docker Compose, SAGA, jQuery, html, css, Fomantic-UI.

Senior Software Engineer at Unico IDtech - October/2020 to March/2022

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil (Remote)

- Development of features and fixes in project and systems that support machine learning engines.
- Participation in architecture definitions of squad projects.
- Monitoring and observability of projects in order to maintain their integrity.
- Assistance to support teams on duty.

Technologies and tools used: Python, Golang, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker compose, ContainerD, Nerdctl, Kubernetes, GCP, UTM, Bash scripting, New Relic, Swagger, git.

Senior Software Engineer at PicPay – August/2020 to September/2021

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil (Remote)

- Development of features and fixes in microservices, systems, panels, and dashboards of squad.
- Participation in discuss meetings about architecture solutions for projects of squad and unit business.
- Participation in technical and business refinement meetings with the product team.
- Development of spot features and fixes in microservices from other squads and unit business.
- Monitoring of availability and performance of microservices from squad.
- Participation in technical interviews and test reviews of new candidates.
- Participation, discuss and talks in meetings of PHP.

Technologies and tools used: Golang, PHP, Laravel, Lumen, Symfony, Docker, Docker compose, Beanstalkd, Minio, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL, Kubernetes, AWS EC2/S3/Kinesis, Bash scripting, New Relic, Swagger, git.

Senior Developer at M4U – March/2020 to July/2020

Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Remote)

- Analysis, discuss, development, fixes and refactor in applications and microservices with squad according to the demands.
- Management and monitoring applications, microservices and resources of ecosystem under responsibility of squad.
- Documentation of flows and process after development.
- Participation in meets for analysis, discuss and presentation of architecture solutions for ecosystem of microservices and other projects.
- Integration with other members in other squads in chapter for management and operation in legacy systems.

Technologies and tools used: Golang, PHP, Javascript, React, Redux, SASS/SCSS, Docker, NATS, PostgreSQL, Redis, Kubernetes, AWS EC2/VPC/S3/EKS/Kinesis/Lambda, Bash scripting, New Relic, Grafana, Kibana.

Senior Software Engineer at Sympla – November/2018 to February/2020

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Analysis, implementation, documentation, and management of high availability cluster with Kubernetes.
- Implementation of new development processes for new microservices used in cluster.
- Implementation of new application deploy processes in cluster.
- Creation and implementation of new external integration microservices into new architecture.
- Participation of meeting for architecture decisions into new application and infrastructure architecture.

Technologies and tools used: AWS EC2/VPC/S3/ELB/EFS/Kinesis/Lambda/Route53, Kubernetes, PHP 5.6/7.1/7.3, Symfony, Slim, GraphQL, Docker, Terraform, Bash scripting, Golang, Helm, Kops, Kong, Istio, Calico, Minikube, Openstack.

Software Engineer at conta. MOBI – January/2017 to November/2018

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Analysis, technical requirements research, development, and fixes on microservices managed by team, legacy software and help to other teams if necessary.
- Implementation of security polices suggested by consulting in systems and microservices.
- Participation in projects of structuration of new microservices environment.
- Creation and management of Open-source projects maintained by startup.
- Management of microservices and Amazon Web Services resources and management assistance of DevOps structure.
- Research and implementation of new technologies and tools for management microservices environment.

Technologies and tools used: PHP, MySQL, Sqlite, Symfony, NodeJS, NPM, SASS, Javascript, Css, Linux, Git, Nginx, Scrum, Docker, RabbitMQ, RPC, PHPStorm, XenServer, AWS, Jira, Slack, Electron, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Rundeck, Oauth2.

IT Manager at Vector Internet Business – February/2014 to January/2017

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Management of development, production, software support staffs.
- Elaboration process of new services and resources for existent services.
- Pro activity in presentation innovative solutions for issues using meetings or discussion with staff.
- Management and monitoring all IT infrastructure of company in office and in services provided to clients.
- Development of additional resources and fixes on software's using requirements analysis, coding, tests and publish using version control system.

Technologies and tools used: PHP, Javascript, jQuery, css, html, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, AWS, Netbeans, UML, DER.

Software architect at Mayer Systems – August/2013 to February/2014

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Elaboration, planning, development, and implementation of vehicle tracking software and ERP provided from company to clients.
- Management of support process flow for clients and web services, databases, DNS, Linux servers and VoIP systems.

Technologies and tools used: PHP, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, Netbeans, UML, DER.

Software architect at IGTI – IT management Institute – February/2013 to August/2013

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

• Concept, elaboration, planning and implementation of new academic software from institute using technical requirements research, diagrams, mental maps, domain models, proof of concepts and DER.

Technologies and tools used: PHP, CodeIgniter, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, Netbeans, UML, DER.

Junior PHP developer at Vector Internet Business – July/2011 to February/2013

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Support to company's systems, technical requirements research, and creation of UML diagrams, principally class diagrams.
- Coding of UML class diagrams in PHP language with object-oriented programming, MVC architecture and jQuery.
- Creation and management of databases used by systems.
- Elaboration new solutions for company office.
- Management of Linux servers and technologies aggregates, as cloud services, e-mail, backup, DNS, and files versioning.
- Training and support for clients and company production staff.

Technologies and tools used: PHP, Javascript, jQuery, css, html, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Netbeans, UML.

Totvs Microsiga Protheus Consultant at Uniserv Group Unity Surveillance Services Company

December/2009 to July/2011 – Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Management all technology and telecommunication from company.
- Elaboration of solutions related to administration process, technical requirements research and develop of routines and customization for ERP Microsiga Protheus.
- Management of databases.
- Training of new employees in your respective sectors.
- Survey of various reports.

Technologies and tools used: Microsiga Protheus, Windows Server, SQL Server, Firewall.

Technical Support at Suprema Computing – April/2009 to November/2009

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Preventive and corrective maintenance on the computers of client companies.
- Remote and in person service.
- Installation, deployment, maintenance, and management of Linux servers, as well as their routines.
- Formulation of solutions for everyday problems faced by customers.

Technologies e tools used: Linux, OpenSUSE, Fedora, Ubuntu, samba, squid, iptables, firewall, ftp, internet gateway, VPN, DNS, pop3, imap, smtp, Amavis, ClamAV, SpamAssasin, virtualization, XenServer, backup, Windows, anti-virus, active directory, LDAP, wired networks, PHP, proprietary software.

Technical Support at Brasol – Brazil Solidarity Action – May/2008 to February/2009

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- Maintenance of computers, laptops, and office security utilities.
- Maintenance of the IT sector data server.
- Maintenance of computers to be donated to schools as Telecentres.
- Tests and development of O.S. Linux for use in Telecentres.

Technologies and tools used: Linux, Telecentre environment, Tucunaré Linux, Windows.

Computer Technician at Fortalnet – September/2007 to January/2008

Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil

- Maintenance of software and hardware for AT and ATX computers platform.
- Installation and maintenance of O.S. FreeBSD.

- Configuration and maintenance of Access Point, Access Routers, Aironet, hacks, Wi-Fi, and local networks.
- General services.

Technologies and tools used: Linux, FreeBSD, Unix, iptables, firewall.

Work overseer at Construction company Passarelli – September/2005 to April/2007

Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil

- Management of the time tracking record of the employees of the construction.
- Management of the lobby with the security guards.
- Management of the resources of the construction warehouse.
- · Purchase of resources for the construction on an emergency basis when necessary.
- Operational assistance to engineering and construction teams.
- Operation of a pickup truck, truck, backhoe, and other machinery to help the demands of construction teams.
- Maintenance of construction and office computers.
- Participation in CIPA processes to ensure the safety of employees in carrying out tasks.
- Reports of the administrative actions carried out on the construction with the administration office.
- Other miscellaneous managerial and administrative routines.

Technologies and tools used: Windows, Excel.

IT teacher at Municipal administration of Santa Isabel city – August/2003 to December/2004

Santa Isabel, São Paulo, Brazil

- Formulation and teaching of classes.
- Social Communication.
- Maintenance of the school's computers and network structure.

Technologies and tools used: Windows 95, 98 and ME, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Access 97, Typing software.

Courses and certifications

Branas.io – JavaScript MasterClass

https://app.branas.io/api/public/certificates/695c5314-aa3d-47ff-b279-12775c9bc0a5/share

Branas.io - Clean Code and Clean Architecture

https://app.branas.io/api/public/certificates/bf4a86c2-f6e2-4263-acca-ac010007ff13/share

Udemy – GCP Associate Cloud Engineer – Google Cloud Certification

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-824a52a7-0537-48fe-ba12-29922ae57362

Udemy – Complete Python Bootcamp From Zero to Hero in Python

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-1146ca31-b755-47c9-9224-7868b37a2523

Udemy - Application monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-1101dae8-7db5-410c-8747-34d411041d24

Udemy – SQL & PostgreSQL for Beginners: Become an SQL Expert

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d321b422-8e97-4667-af44-dc5f20d7abf3

Udemy – Go (Golang): Exploring the Google Programming Language

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d7c3916f-6577-40b8-9830-0282fc3158ab

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 1

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/6C80BAB47C55

SymfonyCasts – OOP: Level 2

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/9A36463DCC64

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 3

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/F9A9AAB21C68

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 4

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/0045F0465C82

SymfonyCasts – Symfony 4 Fundamentals: Services, Config & Environments

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/337CB922C102

SymfonyCasts - Symfony 4 Level 1

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/4ECC5FA2C101

SymfonyCasts - Doctrine & the Database

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/E2F671CBC103

iPED - Polytechnic Institute of Distance Education - AutoCAD 2013

https://www.iped.com.br/certificado?numero=624606

4Linux – Zimbra Collaboration Suite – Total Administration

https://certificados.4linux.com.br

Certificate ID: 4L446300025949 - Code of verification: mGedSL42

PHPrime – PHP Essentials.

Bizmart BHS – 6231 e 6232 – Maintaining and Implementing a Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Database.

Totvs – ADVPL I e II, Architecture and Installation, Configurator, DevStudio and customizable reports.

ShapeBlue Brazil – Bootcamp Apache CloudStack On-Line Brazil.

SENAI – Microcomputers assembly and maintenance.

SOS Computers – Installation and deployment of home networks.

Contacts and more information

E-mail – eu+resume@redrat.com.br

LinkedIn public resume – https://br.linkedin.com/in/joubertredrat?locale=en_US

Site - https://redrat.com.br

GitHub – https://github.com/joubertredrat